pscufs.com 2005-12-10

# Privacy

Introduction

PSCU Financial Services is one of the largest 24 x7 call centers and transaction card service providers for credit unions in the U.S. In addition, we are the largest credit union service organization (CUSO) in the nation. PSCU Financial Services is a cooperative organization dedicated to promoting the success of our members by delivering financial services, technology, and operational support for credit unions.

PSCU Financial Services intends for our web site, www.pscufs.com, to complement the services the organization provides. We also believe that online security and privacy are important to the future success of the Internet and electronic commerce, and that online security and privacy are important to our member credit unions and to their members as well.

PSCU Financial Services has a strong commitment to the issues of trust and privacy on the World Wide Web as demonstrated by our agreement with ICSA.net, the worldwide leader in Internet security assurance services, to provide TruSecure™ certification for our security policies and technical internetworking infrastructure.

We are committed to guarding your data, protecting your members' privacy, and developing technology that gives consumers the most powerful, safe, online experience available anywhere.

After all, isn't that what you expect from us?  

* * *

Privacy

PSCU Financial Services defines Privacy as the measures in place to ensure that any information provided to us is maintained in strict confidence and not distributed, shared, or otherwise used without the expressed permission of the information provider.

Should you merely visit our web site, www.pscufs.com, we do not collect any personal information about you. Should you decide you would like additional information about PSCU Financial Services, we will ask you to register online. During registration, the information disclosed, such as your name and e-mail address, is retained.

We also request and retain during registration other demographic information such as address, credit union affiliation, and purpose for your visit. We use demographic information in the aggregate only, for statistical analysis and internal research to help us understand who is using our site and become better equipped to serve your needs. PSCU Financial Services does not sell, distribute, or disclose your personally identifiable information collected at registration to any third parties.

Our website may contain links to other websites. Accordingly, PSCU Financial Services cannot be responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any linked websites and encourages you to read the privacy statements of linked websites to become acquainted with their specific privacy practices.

PSCU Financial Services' InfoLink site for credit card data currently accepts user ID, password, and other types of information (credit card account number(s), and zip code(s), SSN, mother's maiden name, birthdate, e-mail addresses, etc.) that allow the site to verify the credit union members' access privileges.

Any information credit union members provide to register or use any PSCU Financial Services web sites will be used only as required to enable registration or use of the sites. The information provided is stored in our data center in a secure environment. Any email addresses that credit union members provide or will provide on the site are for supporting communication between the credit union member and PSCU Financial Services' Contact Center representatives.

PSCU Financial Services does not share any user-provided information with outside parties.  

* * *

Collection, Use, and Disclosure

Cookies

PSCU Financial Services avoids the use of cookies whenever possible but cannot guarantee that we will not use them. A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on the PSCU Financial Services web site. Once the user closes the browser, the cookie simply terminates. For instance, by setting a cookie on the PSCU Financial Services site, you would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on either site. If you reject the cookie, you may still use either site, but the site's general inability to verify you as the user may result in your inability to participate in any bulletin boards, sweepstakes, contests or drawings either site might sponsor or promote. Cookies also enable a site to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on each site. Also, please understand that some business partners of PSCU Financial Services may use cookies on their respective sites. However, we have no access to or control over these cookies.

IP Addresses

PSCU Financial Services uses Internet Protocol (IP) addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track movement of users, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

Demographic Information

PSCU Financial Services will share aggregated demographic information with their partners. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. These statistics help us evaluate the effectiveness and appeal of various services and segments of our site.

* * *

Security

PSCU Financial Services defines Security as the procedures and hardware and software infrastructure in place to protect sensitive information from the unwanted acquisition, tampering, or use by unauthorized parties.

PSCU Financial Services has technological and operational security functions in place to protect personally identifiable information from loss, misuse, alteration, or destruction. Only authorized employees have access to the data you provide and that access is limited by need. Our employees who have access to the data you provide have agreed to maintain the confidentiality of such information.

PSCU Financial Services' web sites are secure sites, meaning that all exchanges between the end user's web browser and the site are protected by Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) 128-bit encryption.  

* * *

[](http://www3.trusecure.com/cert_info/certified.shtml?CERTID=082101400)TruSecure™ Certification

TruSecure® Corporation is the worldwide leader in Internet security assurance services, including TruSecure, a comprehensive, multi-disciplinary program that helps hundreds of businesses reduce their information security risks and safely implement new Internet technologies and initiatives. TruSecure's ICSA Labs is the security industry's leading product research and certification facility. Information Security Magazine, published monthly by TruSecure, is the industry's leading source for news, analysis, insight and commentary on today's infosecurity marketplace. Through their certification program, TruSecure reviews PSCU Financial Services' security policies, practices, and physical and technical infrastructure and works with PSCU Financial Services to implement a comprehensive and continuous risk reduction program. To review the TruSecure Perimeter Management & Certification Report, click here.

Please visit [www.trusecure.com](http://www.trusecure.com/) for additional information.  

* * *

Accountability & Responsibility

PSCU Financial Services follows guidelines set forth by the TruSecure Corporation that are designed to provide baseline standards of privacy protection adherence. In addition, we comply with applicable privacy regulations and support consumer, government and industry efforts to identify and resolve privacy issues.

Should PSCU Financial Services decide to change our privacy policies, we will post those changes on the home page of our web site so users are always aware of the information each site collects, how our site uses such information, and under what circumstances, if any, our site discloses such information. If at any point PSCU Financial Services decides to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

We recognize that your trust in us is directly proportional to the manner in which we protect the privacy of your consumer information. We will always exceed your expectations.

* * *

Children

PSCU Financial Services recognizes the importance of protecting children's privacy in the interactive, online world. We do not intentionally target or solicit children under the age of 18. Some of our content may be designed to educate young adults on financial and credit-related material.

* * *

FAQs

> Q: Does PSCU Financial Services use cookies in any of their web products?
> 
> A: Whenever possible, PSCU Financial Services avoids the use of cookies in its applications. This is to ensure that our web applications run on as wide a variety of web browsers and viewers as possible.
> 
> * * *
> 
> Q: What kind of security does PSCU Financial Services have in place to safeguard sensitive information, such as account numbers, that users may enter?
> 
> A: Any sites that PSCU Financial Services hosts to support its web products, such as InfoLink and PayLink, are secure sites. This means that all exchanges between the end user's web browser and the sites are protected by Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) 128-bit encryption. PSCU Financial Services further uses Verisign Class-3 Security Certificates to enable 128-bit encrypted SSL sessions in some browsers that only have 56-bit cypher strength, such as Microsoft's browser that is approved for export outside of the United States. This is especially relevant to credit unions that have an overseas membership base.
> 
> * * *
> 
> Q: How does PSCU Financial Services protect its data center from intrusion by hostile forces?
> 
> A: PSCU Financial Services' internetworking architecture includes several components that collectively provide a high degree of protection from unwanted intrusions or malicious hacking attempts. Our routers include packet-filtering capabilities; our firewalls hide all of our internetworks from the public Internet; and we use intrusion detection and scanning hardware and software to detect any threats to security in real-time.
> 
> * * *
> 
> Q: How secure is my bill payment and personal information?
> 
> A: PSCU Financial Services and its electronic billing and payment partner, CheckFree, use several methods to ensure that your members' bill payment information is secure.
> 
>   * User Name and Password - The user name and password that your members use to access Web Bill Pay are unique identifiers that only your member knows. As long as your members do not share their user name and password with anyone, no one but the member can sign in to use Web Bill Pay.
>   * SSL and Encryption - Web Bill Pay uses SSL (secure sockets layer) and 128-bit encryption, which ensures that your connection and information are secure from outside inspection.
>   * Automatic Sign Out - Web Bill Pay automatically signs a user out of a session if the user is inactive longer than ten minutes.
> 

> 
> * * *
> 
> Q: What does PSCU Financial Services do with information it captures during a member's use of any of its Internet products?
> 
> A: Currently, PSCU Financial Services does not share any member-provided information with any outside parties. The information is stored in databases in our secure data center. However, it is possible that in the future PSCU Financial Services may need to share aggregated demographic information with select partners to facilitate the building of programs and campaigns for cultivating lasting customer relationships and loyalty.
> 
> * * *
> 
> Q: Will we use any IP addresses to analyze any of our user trends?
> 
> A: Whether we specifically use IP addresses or some other tracking or auditing data elements, we will need to analyze user behavior within our sites. This is to enable us to track consumer volume, determine requirements for additional hardware and software, create usage reports for subscribing institutions, and measure the success of our products.
> 
> * * *
> 
> Q: Will any of PSCU Financial Services' web sites hyperlink to other web sites?
> 
> A: Yes, but in most cases the link will be transparent to the user. In other words, a PSCU Financial Services site may transfer control to another partner's site to manage a particular element of a session, such as bill payment using the CheckFree bill payment engine.
